# **MIKE TSOU**

**(**626) 278-6737 **9** San Francisco Bay Area in miketsou mikeytsou

### **SUMMARY**

I'm a Software Engineer with an emphasis on Front End Development. I have a Communications degree and three years experience with data collection and analysis relating to market research strategies. My passion for programming stems from my love for all things tech. My primary focus is to build web applications with the latest technologies and work with a company that will enable me to grow and develop my skills.

### **SKILLS**

PROFICIENT: JavaScript, RubyOnRails, Express, React, Redux, Jquery, Ajax, MongoDB, HTML5, CSS3, RSpec, Jasmine, Sass, Bootstrap, SemanticUI, MVC, PostgreSQL, Git, Heroku, Node, Agile, Lodash

**EXPOSURE:** ReactNative, Materialize, Xcode, Angular, Python

## **PROJECTS**

PORTFOLIO (CLICK TO VIEW) Oct 2017 - Oct 2017

My personal website detailing my background, skills, projects, and my contact information.

Tech Stack: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and Jquery

**EFEEDBACK (CLICK TO VIEW)** Aug 2017 - Sep 2017

A MERN stack application that allows users to send out bulk email surveys to collect some amount of feedback from their customers.

Tech Stack: Node, Express, Passport, MongoDB, Mongoose, StripeAPI, SendGridAPI, React, Redux, ReactRouter, HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript

MYBLOGGER (CLICK TO VIEW) Jul 2017 - Jul 2017

A blogging app that allows users to create blog entries as well as read and comment on other users blog entries.

Tech Stack: Node, Express, Passport, Quill, MongoDB, Mongoose, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and Jquery

DAILY HABITS (CLICK TO VIEW) Jun 2017 - Jun 2017

A journaling application that allows users to keep track of their daily activities and see their weekly progress/statistics via web browser or texting with a mobile device.

Tech Stack: RubyOnRails, ReactNative, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TwilioAPI, GoogleMapsAPI, WeatherUndergroundAPI, and PostgreSQL

### CRABALICIOUS FILMS (CLICK TO VIEW)

Jun 2017 - Jun 2017

A web application that allows users to rate and review films, comment on other users reviews, and sort by categories.

Tech Stack: RubyOnRails, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, PostgreSQL, and JavaScript

## **EMPLOYMENT**

#### NETPOP **Project Manager**

San Francisco Apr 2013 - Aug 2016

- Managing and contributing to the daily execution processes of design, programming, quality control, data collecting/processing, analysis, and
- Oversee employees, translators, and 3rd party vendors for qualitative and quantitative market research studies relating to user experience, customer satisfaction, and product development.
- Successful launch of projects by meeting deadlines, hitting targeted guotas, and developing team dynamics.

#### **FARMERS INSURANCE** Insurance Agent

Los Angeles Sep 2008 - Dec 2009

• Selling life, property and casualty, health, automotive, and other types of insurance policies.

- Perform administrative tasks such as maintaining records and handling policy renewals.
- Calculate premiums and establish payment methods.
- Averaged three clients a week making cold calls and generating leads.

#### **ORINDA COUNTRY CLUB Customer Service**

• Provide service for all club members needing assistance.

- Running errands around the area for the pro shop.
- Clean and store members property for their next arrival.
- Set up and run tournaments.

## **EDUCATION**

San Francisco State University

Bachelor of Arts Communications 2012

Dev Bootcamp

18 week immersive web development bootcamp

Orinda Apr 2007 - May 2008